David Bjerregaard Madsen

Borggata 6, 0650 Oslo +47 46825531 david.b.madsen@gmail.com

About me

Extroverted and ambitious software developer with an academic engineering background and broad spectrum of interests. I have 3+ years of professional experience developing solutions for a variety of clients, specializing in the Microsoft ecosystem.

Both during and outside of my professional career I have attained extensive experience working in and leading teams through numerous projects. Almost-daily contact with clients on every project I've been involved with has given me a good understanding of the client-consultant relationship. I value professionalism and set myself to a high standard in this regard.

In short, I am a highly motivated and driven developer who is eager to attain new knowledge and meet new people.

Experience

September 2021 - to date

Netcompany Norway, Consultant

Full-stack software developer consultant with main focus on .NET, EF Core, React, MS SQL and Microsoft Azure, with occasional dabbling into Python.

- Current project: Key part of the developer team for a billing solution for a major toll service provider
- Mostly responsible for backend development with occasional frontend tasks when required (Azure Functions, Azure Webapps, MS SQL, .NET Core, Entity)
- Devops tasks including CI/CD pipelines and deployment to development environments (Azure DevOps, Bicep)
- Responsible for coordinating and supporting both customer and internal test team on monthly releases

January 2022 - to date

Flux Collective AS, Co-owner & Technical Lead

Co-owner of a small Oslo-based electronic record label where I am involved in administrative and technical operations in the company.

- Develop and maintain the company website (<u>flux-collective.com</u>) and managing other business solutions
- Oversee financial planning, budgeting, and administrative operations
- In development: a custom web application for sales data analysis utilizing Bandcamp's API. (.NET + React)

October 2020 - September 2021

Data Respons R&D Services, Development Engineer

Software developer/engineering consultant with focus on full-stack development and cloud solutions.

- Responsible for the web/cloud solution for our in-house GPS Tracker project (October-March) (Python/flask, websockets, React, GCP)
- Deployed as software engineer at a leading company in the automotive industry, assisting the engineering team with product validation, documentation and testing

August 2016 - October 2020

SplashTrend Licensing, Director of Digital Media - Freelance

Side project with study colleagues involving online media licensing, content production and promotion mainly on YouTube.

- Responsible for content acquisition and communication with social media users
- Video editing, branding and and visual content creation for our YouTube channels
- Developed proof-of-concept automated content recognition software to identify assets in online videos (Python)

Education

August 2018 - June 2020

Norwegian Uni. of Science and Technology, Industrial Cybernetics

- Master's degree in linear system design with electives in software development
- Master's thesis: Procedural City Generation in Unity Engine explored existing and new methods of procedurally generating cities using Unity Engine as the development platform (C#/Unity)

August 2014 - June 2017

Oslo & Akershus University College, Mechanical Engineering

 Bachelor's degree in mechanical engineering with electives in mathematics, computational fluid dynamics and robotics

Skills

Strong backend mainly focused around the .NET + Azure ecosystem which I'm currently working with. In Microsoft Azure, I'm experienced with a wide variety of key cloud services including Azure Functions, App Service, Service Bus, Azure SQL, Cosmos DB etc.

I also to a lesser extent do frontend work in React (js/ts), where I have experience from both professional solutions and side projects.

I'm comfortable utilizing other languages and platforms such as Python, where I have experience with web development frameworks such as Flask and asyncio. I also frequently use Python to automate day-to-day tasks such as automated API calls, batch database operations, etc.

- Languages: C#.NET, Python, JavaScript/TypeScript
- Cloud: Mainly Microsoft Azure, but also familiar with AWS and GCP
- SQL/database: MS SQL/PostgreSQL, Azure Cosmos DB
- DevOps: Azure Devops, Github
- Other platforms, etc: Webflow, Wordpress
- Key words: .NET Core, EF Core, cloud, devops, application development, full-stack, MVC

Certifications

- AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals (December 19, 2022)
- AZ-204: Developing Solutions for Microsoft Azure (Planned: September 21, 2023)

Languages

- Norwegian Native
- English Fluent

Interests

• Music Production & DJing: Regular performances at nightclubs in Oslo and hosting events.